<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DESI Trust</title>
    <link>https://desitrust.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DESI Trust</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://desitrust.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://desitrust.org/about-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://desitrust.org/about-copy/</guid>
      <description>Developing Ecologically Sustainable Industry DESI means indigenous in some Indian languages. It is also an acronym for Developing Ecologically Sustainable Industries. DESI is not just a handloom store, it is much more. Desi is a registered trust. It strives to provide decent livelihood for handloom workers, work in ecologically sensitive areas and introduce alternate forms of employment, provide a economically viable alternative to villagers to ensure they do not migrate, focus on eco-friendly practices and advocate rights of handloom workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://desitrust.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://desitrust.org/about/</guid>
      <description>History DESI Trust was started in 1997 in Bengaluru with the purpose of marketing naturally-dyed handwoven products made by Charaka Womens&#39; Society in a way that appealed to the urban market. It aimed to build a working relationship with informed and sympathetic patrons from the city. Gradually, it opened outlets all across Karnataka in 15 locations. These DESI outlets sell handloom, handcrafted and food products from across India in addition to Charaka’s products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handloom</title>
      <link>https://desitrust.org/handloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://desitrust.org/handloom/</guid>
      <description>Handloom is the name given to fabric that is woven by a hand-operated weaving machine or &amp;ldquo;loom&amp;rdquo;. It is also referred to as &amp;ldquo;hand woven&amp;rdquo;. Handloom fabric came into being during 19th century when the British started producing cotton yarn using automatic machines at factories in England and dumping it on our weavers. Our country has a rich tradition of handloom and a variety of fabric, each a specialty of the region of its origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initiatives</title>
      <link>https://desitrust.org/initiatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://desitrust.org/initiatives/</guid>
      <description>Bonus Programme  Every year, based on the amount of production achieved, each artisan (weaver, pre-loom, post-loom, admin staff, helpers) are provided bonus during the Deepavali festival. DESI Trust Managers travel to the remote villages to personally thank each artisan and hand over the bonus to them. This is a way to acknowledge their performance and also provide encouragement for them to produce better quantity and quality in the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trust</title>
      <link>https://desitrust.org/trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://desitrust.org/trust/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
